Three lives. One destiny.
Head in the Clouds is a drama, romance, war film directed by John Duigan.
Gilda Bessé shares her Paris apartment with an Irish
schoolteacher, Guy Malyon, and Mia, a refugee from Spain.
As the world drifts toward war, Gilda defiantly pursues her hedonistic
lifestyle and her burgeoning career as a photographer.
But Guy and Mia feel impelled to join the fight against
fascism, and the three friends are separated.
Gilda Bessé, played by Charlize Theron.
Mia, played by Penélope Cruz.
Guy Malyon, played by Stuart Townsend.
Major Thomas Bietrich, played by Thomas Kretschmann.
Max, played by Peter Cockett.
Julian Ellsworth, played by Gabriel Hogan.
Head in the Clouds is a 2004 Canadian-British war drama
film written and directed by John Duigan.
The original screenplay focuses on the choices young lovers must make as they find
themselves surrounded by increasing political unrest in late-1930s Europe.
The film was a critical and box office failure.
The film explores themes of nazi, photographer, world war
ii, spanish civil war (1936-39), love.
The tone is emotional.